Khaleed Oyeleke

Data Scientist

I am a Data Scientist with an engineering background. Versatile individual with experience collecting, transforming, and organizing data for analysis to help make informed decisions. Excellent understanding and proficiency of platforms for effective data analyses, including SQL, spreadsheets, Tableau, Python and R. Adept at building machine learning models. Constantly praised in past internships as a fast-learner, self starter and team-player.



oyelekekhaleed@gmail.com 🔀

+2348139562882

Ilorin, Nigeria

sites.google.com/view/meetkhaleed/home

linkedin.com/in/khaleed-oyeleke-27b182195 in

github.com/khal33d-hub

EDUCATION

Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering University of Ilorin

10/2015 - 10/2021

Second Class (Upper)Honors

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Science Intern

Gradient Boost

10/2020 - 03/2021

An E-learning platform for short courses and hands-on projects Achievements/Tasks

- Administered various Data cleaning and Data Manipulation tasks with pandas and numpy;
- Tasked with dynamic web-scrapping with Selenium and Beautifulsoap;
- Design and Built end to end machine learning Model on StockMarket prices prediction to increase profitability of traders:
- Deployed the stock market project on Heroku using python's Streamlit;

Data Analysis Intern TakenMind Technologies

12/2019 - 01/2020

Remote

Remote

a part of the Global Internship 2019 Program(Recognized by United Nations SDG#26437)

Achievements/Tasks

- Devised monthly practice reports using advanced Excel spreadsheet functions like VLOOKUP and Pivot tables;
- Optimized statistical data analysis, design, and visualization with Excel and power Bi;
- Successfully adhered to deadlines and assessments and received a personal letter of recommendation;

Undergraduate Intern Center4Tech

04/2019 - 09/2019

Lagos, Nigeria

Achievements/Tasks

- Coached students on Games Development and 3D animation (Construct2, Unity 3D Engine, Iclone 7, blender,photoshop) applying variety of instructional techniques, including hands-on curriculum;
- Implemented and optimized new curriculum and day to day instructions to align educational strategies with industry best practices;
- Built Educational 2D android games for teaching younger students complex tasks like mathematics;

SKILLS AND EXPERTISE



PERSONAL PROJECTS

Stock Market prices Forecasting 🗹

 Leverage my knowledge of data wrangling, database, API interactions and Machine learning models to build an end to end project to increase confidence for stock market investors;

Cryptocurrency Case Study 🗹

 This involves web-scrapping coinmarketcap website for updated data on top 20 coins, visualizing and plotting.

Exploratory Data Analysis 🗹

- Analyzing and Visualizing Google play store data;
- Analyzing and Visualizing History Nobel Prices Winner;
- Analyzing and Visualizing Scala's Project;

Data Dashboards and Data-storytelling

List of all my Tableau Dashboards and Stories;

Social media web-app

- A web-app built to function like reddit social media web-app;
- Leveraged my knowledge of HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and Jquery for responsive web design and Python's Django and SQL as database for backend technologies;

Blog web-app 🛂

• A web-app built to function as a single user blog on Nature;

COURSES AND TRAINING

Google data analysis Professional certification

Complete Python Bootcamp: Zero to Hero 🗹

Data Analysis and Visualization

Python for Data Structures and Algorithm 🗗

Django Full Stack Web developer Bootcamp

MongoDB Basics 🗹